my doctor says I can't have HRT because
I had breast cancer in the past is this
correct that's something I hear a lot
from um my patients sometimes if they
complain about menopausal symptoms I ask
them are you on HRT out of interest and
sometimes I hear this no I have had
breast cancer I can't have it right well
this is a very controversial topic and I
don't think that I have the the
definitive answer on it but I mean it
first of all it depends on what kind of
breast cancer you had okay so I mean if
it was not a a hormone dependent cancer
then I think you know you can do
whatever you want if it was a hormon
dependent cancer again I mean I hear
like I I guess it it's really depends on
the patient Comfort because I hear some
anti-aging doctors at the conferences
say oh yes if it's you know if it's been
a few years you can go ahead and do it
um but then I don't know I mean if you
have an estrogen dependent cancer I
think a lot of doctors will be really
nervous to give HRT so I think a couple
of things that you can do um I think you
can give testosterone and I know a
little bit of it does aromatize to to
estrogen but actually a long time ago
they used to treat breast cancer with
testosterone they used to actually
inject this is a long time ago they used
to actually inject the tumors with
testosterone before there was
chemotherapy and it it actually worked
pretty well so I think testosterone is
is one thing and also as triol which is
a very weak estrogen that has
anti-cancer properties I think you can
use uh you can use estriol vaginal cream
uh for for symptoms of vaginal dryness
vaginal atrophy you can use some some
DHEA so like I you know estral like I I
think it is controversial and again I'm
definitely not like not the expert on
this um but but there are some some
workarounds I don't think you have to be
100% hormone free and feel terrible
[Music]
mhm